A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Grants E-G FA732C FA732C
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Grants - E to G
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290120): PROGRAM STAFF AND PROGRAM SUPPORT FOR THE NEW DELHI OFFICE, FISCAL YEAR 1972, 1971 October 01-1972 September 30 (Reel 1138)
    PROGRAM STAFF AND PROGRAM SUPPORT FOR THE NEW DELHI OFFICE, FISCAL YEAR 1972
    $550,000.00;$330,086.15
    Zeidenstein, George
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290125): CLOSE OUT COSTS OF THE ENERGY POLICY PROJECT, 1972 January 01-1976 January 31 (Reel 2098;2099;2100;2101;2102;2212;2213;2214)
    CLOSE OUT COSTS OF THE ENERGY POLICY PROJECT
    $3,025,737.00;$3,025,737.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290147): FELLOWSHIPS FOR YOUNG EUROPEANS FOR RESEARCH ON PROBLEMS COMMON TO ADVANCED INDUSTRIAL SOCIETIES, 1972 March 15-1974 March 14 (Reel 2302;5668)
    FELLOWSHIPS FOR YOUNG EUROPEANS FOR RESEARCH ON PROBLEMS COMMON TO ADVANCED INDUSTRIAL SOCIETIES
    $220,000.00;$170,720.58
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290153): RESEARCH PROJECT ON THE POLITICAL AND SOCIAL SYSTEM OF LEBANON, 1972 March 24-1976 February 24 (Reel 3163;4256)
    RESEARCH PROJECT ON THE POLITICAL AND SOCIAL SYSTEM OF LEBANON
    $82,978.00;$82,978.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290154): SEMINAR/WORKSHOP ON OPERATIONS RESEARCH IN EGYPT, 1972 May 01-1974 September 18 (Reel 1528;3163)
    SEMINAR/WORKSHOP ON OPERATIONS RESEARCH IN EGYPT
    $38,086.00;$38,086.00
    Bunker, Samuel E.;Robarts, Richard C.
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290169): SEMINAR FOR COLOMBIAN FELLOWSHIP AWARDEES IN ECONOMICS AND AGRICULTURAL ECONOMICS CURRENTLY STUDYING IN U. S. GRAD. SCHOOLS, 1972 March 29-1974 May 31 (Reel 1752;3260)
    SEMINAR FOR COLOMBIAN FELLOWSHIP AWARDEES IN ECONOMICS AND AGRICULTURAL ECONOMICS CURRENTLY STUDYING IN U. S. GRAD. SCHOOLS
    $8,944.00;$8,944.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290171): COSTS OF A PROGRAM FOR IMPROVED MANAGEMENT OF FAMILY-PLANNING AND POPULATION PROGRAMS, 1972 March 28-1981 September 30 (Reel 5164;65;66;67;68)
    COSTS OF A PROGRAM FOR IMPROVED MANAGEMENT OF FAMILY-PLANNING AND POPULATION PROGRAMS
    $1,122,750.00;$1,122,750.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290185): DISSERTATION FELLOWSHIPS IN ETHNIC STUDIES, 1972 April 01-1973 March 31 (Reel 1998;1999)
    DISSERTATION FELLOWSHIPS IN ETHNIC STUDIES
    $410,000.00;$394,245.50
    Challenor, Herschelle
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290186): RESEARCH ON AGRICULTURAL MARKETING PROBLEMS IN THE PHILIPPINES, 1972 April 14-1975 December 22 (Reel 1190;3323)
    RESEARCH ON AGRICULTURAL MARKETING PROBLEMS IN THE PHILIPPINES
    $132,876.00;$132,876.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290191): SUPPORT FOR A RESEARCH PROJECT IN THE FIELD OF LAW AND THE ADMINISTRATION OF JUSTICE, 1972 April 17-1978 December 31 (Reel 2684)
    SUPPORT FOR A RESEARCH PROJECT IN THE FIELD OF LAW AND THE ADMINISTRATION OF JUSTICE
    $544,000.00;$544,000.00
    Dodds, R. Harcourt
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290212): REGIONAL WEST AFRICAN FELLOWSHIP PROGRAM, 1972 April 27-1981 December 31 (Reel 3857;4179;5668)
    REGIONAL WEST AFRICAN FELLOWSHIP PROGRAM
    $1,685,000.00;$1,685,000.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290221): ESTABLISHMENT OF A CORE REFERENCE LIBRARY FOR THE MINISTRIES OF THE PEOPLE'S REPUBLIC OF BANGLADESH, 1972 May 26-1974 May 25 (Reel 1318;1319;5328)
    ESTABLISHMENT OF A CORE REFERENCE LIBRARY FOR THE MINISTRIES OF THE PEOPLE'S REPUBLIC OF BANGLADESH
    $50,000.00;$48,405.25
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290241): CONTINUED SUPPORT TO INVESTIGATE ISSUES RELATED TO OCCUPATIONAL HEALTH AND SAFETY, 1972 May 30-1974 September 20 (Reel 1090)
    CONTINUED SUPPORT TO INVESTIGATE ISSUES RELATED TO OCCUPATIONAL HEALTH AND SAFETY
    $53,679.00;$53,679.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290245): EDUCATIONAL RESEARCH AWARDS AND FELLOWSHIPS IN BRAZIL, 1972 May 30-1983 December 31 (Reel 4472;5199;5200)
    EDUCATIONAL RESEARCH AWARDS AND FELLOWSHIPS IN BRAZIL
    $1,182,000.00;$1,182,000.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290255): DEVELOPMENT OF APPLIED STATISTICAL SERVICES AT FOUR INDONESIAN UNIVERSITIES, 1972 June 21-1981 June 30 (Reel 4314;7734;8057)
    DEVELOPMENT OF APPLIED STATISTICAL SERVICES AT FOUR INDONESIAN UNIVERSITIES
    Bigalke, Terance William
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290256): SUPPLEMENTAL SUPPORT FOR LEARNING RESEARCH AND ITS APPLICATIONS, 1978 December 19-1980 December 18 (Reel 2119;2124;3035;5143)
    SUPPLEMENTAL SUPPORT FOR LEARNING RESEARCH AND ITS APPLICATIONS
    $36,504.64;$36,504.64
    Global; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290257): CONFERENCE OF THE LANGUAGE ASSOCIATION OF EASTERN AFRICA, 1972 June 23-1972 December 22 (Reel 1330;1331;3957;3958;3959;4080)
    CONFERENCE OF THE LANGUAGE ASSOCIATION OF EASTERN AFRICA
    $17,000.00;$16,834.09
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290258): STUDY OF THE EMPLOYMENT PROBLEM IN LESS DEVELOPED COUNTRIES, 1972 July 01-1975 June 30 (Reel 1553;1554;1555;3035)
    STUDY OF THE EMPLOYMENT PROBLEM IN LESS DEVELOPED COUNTRIES
    $112,810.00;$112,810.00
    Newmann, John M.
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290318): STATION INDEPENDENCE PROJECT, 1972 June 01-1975 June 30 (Reel 1756)
    STATION INDEPENDENCE PROJECT
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290319): A TASK FORCE TO DETERMINE FORD FOUNDATION POLICY IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS, 1972 June 27-1973 November 27 (Reel 1758;1759;1760;1761)
    A TASK FORCE TO DETERMINE FORD FOUNDATION POLICY IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290320): PROGRAM ANALYSIS AND PLANNING PAPER FOR STATE AND LOCAL GOVERNMENT, 1972 July 01-1977 September 30 (Reel 2888;4815)
    PROGRAM ANALYSIS AND PLANNING PAPER FOR STATE AND LOCAL GOVERNMENT
    $51,262.42;$51,262.42
    Brezenoff, Stanley N.;Winnick, Louis
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290322): PROJECT PERSONNEL ATTACHED TO THE WEST AFRICA REGIONAL OFFICE, 1972 April 01-1979 November 17 (Reel 3759;3857)
    PROJECT PERSONNEL ATTACHED TO THE WEST AFRICA REGIONAL OFFICE
    $1,496,939.00;$1,496,939.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290326): SUPPORT OF EXPLORATORY ACTIVITIES OF THE FOUNDATION TASK FORCE ON EQUAL OPPORTUNITY FOR WOMEN, 1972 July 01-1974 July 01 (Reel 4017)
    SUPPORT OF EXPLORATORY ACTIVITIES OF THE FOUNDATION TASK FORCE ON EQUAL OPPORTUNITY FOR WOMEN
    Education and Public Policy;International - Office of the Vice President [ID/OVP];National Affairs [NA]
    $49,953.5;$49,953.5
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290327): ASSISTANCE TO THE CENTRAL BUREAU OF STATISTICS (INDONESIA) IN ANALYSIS OF CENSUS DATA, 1972 June 01-1973 May 31 (Reel 2688;4387)
    ASSISTANCE TO THE CENTRAL BUREAU OF STATISTICS (INDONESIA) IN ANALYSIS OF CENSUS DATA
    $29,000.00;$28,027.14
    Ashabranner, Brent K.;Gaberman, Barry D.
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290349): STUDY ON THE FUTURE OF THE INTERNATIONAL ECONOMIC ORDER, 1972 July 31-1976 July 12 (Reel 3008)
    STUDY ON THE FUTURE OF THE INTERNATIONAL ECONOMIC ORDER
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290385): STUDY OF RESEARCH RESOURCES RELATED TO SOIL-WATER PLANT RELATIONSHIPS IN ARID REGIONS, 1972 July 31-1974 September 20 (Reel 1249)
    STUDY OF RESEARCH RESOURCES RELATED TO SOIL-WATER PLANT RELATIONSHIPS IN ARID REGIONS
    $168,000.00;$168,000.00
    Hardin, Lowell S.;Robarts, Richard C.
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290388): TRAINING AND RESEARCH IN AGRICULTURAL DEVELOPMENT, EASTERN AFRICA., 1972 July 31-1980 March 30 (Reel 2158;4080;4103;4166)
    TRAINING AND RESEARCH IN AGRICULTURAL DEVELOPMENT, EASTERN AFRICA.
    Gerhart, John D.;Hardin, Lowell S.;Horovitz, Richard A.
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290404): ASSISTANCE TO FIVE PROVINCIAL INDONESIAN UNIVERSITIES AIDING REGIONAL DEVELOPMENT, 1972 August 10-1978 December 31 (Reel 3750;3829;3878;4040;5201;6074;7743;8058)
    ASSISTANCE TO FIVE PROVINCIAL INDONESIAN UNIVERSITIES AIDING REGIONAL DEVELOPMENT
    $603,000.00;$603,000.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290413): CONSULTANCIES, INDIVIDUAL/ORGANIZATIONAL GRANTS, TRAVEL, CONF. ANDEXPENSES TO EXPLORE ISSUES OF LOWER MIDDLE INCOME WORKING CLASS, 1972 August 29-1980 September 30 (Reel 4815;4933;5147;5201)
    CONSULTANCIES, INDIVIDUAL/ORGANIZATIONAL GRANTS, TRAVEL, CONF. ANDEXPENSES TO EXPLORE ISSUES OF LOWER MIDDLE INCOME WORKING CLASS
    $1,197,540.00;$1,197,540.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290438): DEVELOPMENT OF RESEARCH ON DATE PALM DISEASE IN ALGERIA, 1972 August 30-1978 September 30 (Reel 2157;3982;3983;5244)
    DEVELOPMENT OF RESEARCH ON DATE PALM DISEASE IN ALGERIA
    Bronzi, Piero
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290439): DEVELOPMENT OF AUDIO-VISUAL MATERIALS RELATED TO WHEAT PRODUCTION PROGRAM IN NORTH AFRICA, 1972 August 30-1974 September 20 (Reel 1229;1637)
    DEVELOPMENT OF AUDIO-VISUAL MATERIALS RELATED TO WHEAT PRODUCTION PROGRAM IN NORTH AFRICA
    $64,000.00;$64,000.00
    Bronzi, Piero;Hardin, Lowell S.;Robarts, Richard C.
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290446): ENGLISH LANGUAGE TEXTBOOK DEVELOPMENT FOR SECONDARY SCHOOLS, 1972 September 07-1975 August 21 (Reel 2113;4005;5244;7419)
    ENGLISH LANGUAGE TEXTBOOK DEVELOPMENT FOR SECONDARY SCHOOLS
    $125,886.00;$125,886.00
    de Spoelberch, Guillaume
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290447): SUPPORT TO INVESTIGATE THEORY AND PRACTICE IN THE FIELD OF JOB SATISFACTION AND RECOMMEND POSSIBLE COURSES, 1972 September 07-1975 October 03 (Reel 2975;2976)
    SUPPORT TO INVESTIGATE THEORY AND PRACTICE IN THE FIELD OF JOB SATISFACTION AND RECOMMEND POSSIBLE COURSES
    $42,923.00;$42,923.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07290451): LANGUAGE PLANNING IN MALAYSIA, 1972 September 26-1979 January 12 (Reel 2889;3492)
    LANGUAGE PLANNING IN MALAYSIA
    $300,416.00;$300,416.00
    Gaberman, Barry D.;Geithner, Peter F.
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390001): FISCAL YEAR 1973 REGIONAL CONFERENCES, 1972 October 01-1973 September 30 (Reel 4172;4204;4924)
    FISCAL YEAR 1973 REGIONAL CONFERENCES
    $152,100.00;$152,100.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390002): FISCAL YEAR 1973 DELEGATED-AUTHORITY GRANTS, 1972 October 01-1973 September 30 (Reel 1343;1370;1966;3345;3633;3788;3906;4161;4277;4612;5202;5230;5650)
    FISCAL YEAR 1973 DELEGATED-AUTHORITY GRANTS
    Lebanon;West Africa (Lagos);Tunisia;Turkey;Brazil (Rio de Janeiro);Colombia;Mexico and Central America (Mexico City);Andean Region & Southern Cone-Peru;Andean Region and Southern Cone (Santiago);Population [POP];International - Office of the Vice Presiden
    $764,679.00;$764,679.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390003): FISCAL YEAR 1973 TRAVEL AND STUDY GRANTS, 1972 October 01-1973 September 30 (Reel 1343;3345;3788;3906;4172;4277;4639;5081;5189;5191;5277)
    FISCAL YEAR 1973 TRAVEL AND STUDY GRANTS
    Lebanon;Eastern Africa (Nairobi);Andean Region & Southern Cone-Peru;Mexico and Central America (Mexico City);Andean Region and Southern Cone (Santiago);Colombia;Brazil (Rio de Janeiro);Latin America & The Caribbean [LAC];Population [POP];International - O
    $3,682,276.00;$3,682,276.00
    Bangladesh; Brazil; Chile; Travel and study grants --Brazil; Travel and study grants --Bangladesh; Travel and study grants --Chile; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390009): FISCAL YEAR 1973 LOGISTIC SUPPORT (PROJECT STAFF), 1972 October 01-1973 September 30 (Reel 1763;2097;3035;4172)
    FISCAL YEAR 1973 LOGISTIC SUPPORT (PROJECT STAFF)
    Thailand;Bangladesh [ASIA/BA];Philippines (Manila);Pakistan;Malaysia;Indonesia (Jakarta);India, Nepal and Sri Lanka (New Delhi);West Africa (Lagos);Tunisia;Lebanon;Eastern Africa (Nairobi);Andean Region and Southern Cone (Santiago);Andean Region & Souther
    $1,699,990.00;$1,699,990.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390010): GRADUATE FELLOWSHIPS FOR LATIN AMERICA AND THE CARIBBEAN, 1972 October 01-1979 June 01 (Reel 4172;4187)
    GRADUATE FELLOWSHIPS FOR LATIN AMERICA AND THE CARIBBEAN
    Andean Region & Southern Cone-Peru;Andean Region and Southern Cone (Santiago);Mexico and Central America (Mexico City);Colombia;Brazil (Rio de Janeiro)
    $1,299,278.00;$1,299,278.00
    Cleaves, Peter S.;Dye, Richard W.;Gardner, James A.;Himes, James R.
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390011): AUDIOVISUAL DISSEMINATION OF EXPERIENCE AND RESULTS OF FOUNDATION-SUPPORTED ACTIVITIES, 1972 October 01-1973 March 31 (Reel 5182;5184;5185;5929)
    AUDIOVISUAL DISSEMINATION OF EXPERIENCE AND RESULTS OF FOUNDATION-SUPPORTED ACTIVITIES
    Education and Public Policy;International - Office of the Vice President [ID/OVP];National Affairs [NA];Office of Communications (pre 1979);Office Of Vice President -Finance & Administration
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390013): PROGRAM STAFF AND PROGRAM SUPPORT FOR THE NEW DELHI OFFICE, FISCAL YEAR 1973, 1972 October 01-1973 September 30 (Reel 1234)
    PROGRAM STAFF AND PROGRAM SUPPORT FOR THE NEW DELHI OFFICE, FISCAL YEAR 1973
    $300,000.00;$247,997.79
    Bresnan, John J.;Scatena, Elisa M.;Staples, Eugene S.
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390027): SUPPORT OF FACULTY FELLOWSHIPS FOR RESEARCH ON PROBLEMS OF WOMEN IN SOCIETY AND DISSERTATION FELLOWSHIPS IN WOMEN'S STUDIES, 1972 October 01-1975 September 30 (Reel 1912;1913;1914;1915;1916;5356;5357;5358;5359;5360;5361;5362;5363)
    SUPPORT OF FACULTY FELLOWSHIPS FOR RESEARCH ON PROBLEMS OF WOMEN IN SOCIETY AND DISSERTATION FELLOWSHIPS IN WOMEN'S STUDIES
    $790,001.00;$790,001.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390035): INTERIM SUPPORT FOR THE STAFF OF THE UNITED NATIONS CONFERENCE ON THE HUMAN ENVIRONMENT (MICHAEL SAKELLAROPOULO), 1972 August 01-1975 June 16 (Reel 1069)
    INTERIM SUPPORT FOR THE STAFF OF THE UNITED NATIONS CONFERENCE ON THE HUMAN ENVIRONMENT (MICHAEL SAKELLAROPOULO)
    $39,810.00;$39,810.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390039): REVIEW OF PROBLEMS OF PUBLIC MANAGEMENT IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES, 1972 October 30-1973 May 29 (Reel 1969)
    REVIEW OF PROBLEMS OF PUBLIC MANAGEMENT IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES
    $80,000.00;$67,685.42
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390091): SUPPORT TO STRENGTHEN CAPACITIES FOR RURAL DEVELOPMENT RESEARCH PLANNING AND POLICY FORMATION IN SOUTHEAST ASIA, 1972 December 18-1980 December 31 (Reel 3535;3536;4357;4416;4417;4438;4452)
    SUPPORT TO STRENGTHEN CAPACITIES FOR RURAL DEVELOPMENT RESEARCH PLANNING AND POLICY FORMATION IN SOUTHEAST ASIA
    $368,400.00;$368,400.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390092): SUPPORT TO STRENGTHEN ENVIRONMENTAL POLICY FORMULATION AND MANAGEMENT CAPACITIES IN SOUTHEAST ASIA, 1972 December 18-1980 July 31 (Reel 4397;3500;4357;4484;4485;5511)
    SUPPORT TO STRENGTHEN ENVIRONMENTAL POLICY FORMULATION AND MANAGEMENT CAPACITIES IN SOUTHEAST ASIA
    Thailand;Education and Public Policy
    $940,000.00;$940,000.00
    Environmental policy -- Asia, Southeastern; Environmental policy -- India; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390120): DEVELOPMENT OF RESEARCH BASE FOR EDUCATIONAL PLANNING IN THAILAND, 1973 February 01-1980 December 31 (Reel 3834;3841;4622;4623;4899;4900)
    DEVELOPMENT OF RESEARCH BASE FOR EDUCATIONAL PLANNING IN THAILAND
    $853,000.00;$853,000.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390154): TO ESTABLISH A SERVICE TO GATHER/DISTRIBUTE INFO. AND TECHNICAL RESOURCES ON SIGNIFICANT PROJECTS IN CORRECTIONAL REFORM, 1973 March 15-1975 May 15 (Reel 2712)
    TO ESTABLISH A SERVICE TO GATHER/DISTRIBUTE INFO. AND TECHNICAL RESOURCES ON SIGNIFICANT PROJECTS IN CORRECTIONAL REFORM
    $262,998.00;$262,998.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390178): INDONESIAN SOCIAL SCIENCE RESEARCH TRAINING, 1973 January 01-1983 September 30 (Reel 4697;5037;5261;5270;5342;7744;7748;8058)
    INDONESIAN SOCIAL SCIENCE RESEARCH TRAINING
    $1,180,450.00;$1,180,450.00
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390182): TO UNDERWRITE THE COSTS INCURRED BY THE TASK FORCE ON RACE AND ETHNICITY, 1975 June 02-1976 June 01 (Reel 1096)
    TO UNDERWRITE THE COSTS INCURRED BY THE TASK FORCE ON RACE AND ETHNICITY
    $9,653.19;$9,653.19
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390195): DOCUMENTATION AND EVALUATION OF THE TUTORIAL COMMUNITY PROJECT, 1973 February 26-1977 September 30 (Reel 2329)
    DOCUMENTATION AND EVALUATION OF THE TUTORIAL COMMUNITY PROJECT
    $150,000.00;$129,532.57
  - Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390201): USA-USSR SEMINAR ON MANAGEMENT EDUCATION, 1973 February 15-1977 May 07 (Reel 1372;5202)
    USA-USSR SEMINAR ON MANAGEMENT EDUCATION
    $80,730.00;$80,730.00
    deJanosi, Peter E.;Lederer, Ivo J.
    Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (07390227): PROVISION OF RESEARCH FUNDS FOR A BROAD HISTORICAL AND ANALYTICAL EXAMINATION IN THE FIELD OF